<?xml version="1.0"?>
<content collectionGUID="A89F4811-9A01-435F-A5D5-8F05AB87754F">
  <lastEdited clientType="local-build-20130405" date="2013-04-05 16:32:16 +0000"/>
  <textBox id="generic-header-attribute" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>SMALL data</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-body-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>Around &lt;a href="perma://BLPageReference/E9DE051E-537F-410E-A9B0-F98AB25871C8"&gt;this time&lt;/a&gt;, I started attending &lt;a href="https://www.hackerschool.com/"&gt;Hacker School&lt;/a&gt;.  So when the &lt;a href="http://www.nyrr.org/"&gt;NYRR&lt;/a&gt; decided to stonewall me, I decided to hack them.  Ok. Not really &#x201C;hack&#x201D; but more like &#x201C;take advantage of the fact that all their race data is just a few clicks away.&#x201D;  So, with the help of &lt;a href="http://pepijndevos.nl/"&gt;another Hacker Schooler&lt;/a&gt;, I wrote &lt;a href="https://github.com/yaelelmatad/nyrr_scrapy/tree/master/nyrr_stats/spiders"&gt;my first scraper&lt;/a&gt;.  I decided to write it in python using the &lt;a href="http://scrapy.org/"&gt;scrapy framework&lt;/a&gt;. I&#x2019;d played a bit with python in grad school but mostly to write tiny data analysis scripts and never for anything major - certainly never for anything that involved sending requests over the internet!&#xD;Luckily my python scripts worked and after passing &#x201C;self&#x201D; around a few dozen times and I finally managed to get the thing going. In the end, I scraped all the race results from the late 80s all the way up to July 2012.  The data was a bit of a mess, so of course I spent quite a bit of time &lt;a href="https://github.com/yaelelmatad/nyrr_scrapy/tree/master/pythonCSV"&gt;cleaning it up&lt;/a&gt;.&#xD;Then, of course, I had to figure out what to do with this massive CSV file.  Ok.  Not massive, but there are some 2,000,000 + rows in my CSV file. It was time to learn something about databases....  &#xD;I ended up settling on a MySQL database, for no particularly good reason other than my data was all relational and I could use the pretty &lt;a href="http://www.sequelpro.com/"&gt;Sequel Pro&lt;/a&gt; app. Here&#x2019;s my personal data through July 2012, for example.&#xD;&#xD;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-title-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>My first database</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-datefield-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>Monday, April 1, 2013</richText>
  </textBox>
</content>
